Mark Anthony Rathbone

Contact Details

PHONE NUMBER

+447984 682775

EMAIL ADDRESS

MarkAnthonyRathbone@gmail.com

WEBSITES

<u>Linkedin</u> / <u>Github</u> Mark**R**athbone.uk



Summary

I am an AWS and Microsoft Certified Cloud Practitioner. In addition, I am also a CompTIA A+ Certified IT Technician, and I have 8 years of experience with tech troubleshooting and problem solving.

This year I completed the AWS re/Start programme run by Generation. During this course I studied Linux, Shell, Networking, Security, Python. I also learnt about the monitoring, support, and application of AWS services in Cloud environments. After this training course I successfully passed the AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner exam. Since, I have continued to self-study and have covered topics such as Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform and Ansible. I also recently passed the Microsoft Azure Fundamentals exam.

My previous experiences have equipped me with a range of technical skills in both physical and cloud environments. By working in customer facing roles I have become proficient in problem-solving under pressure and communicating with a varied audience. In my next role I am looking to begin working in a Cloud environment so I can put my new skills to the test, and continue to learn and develop.

Key Skills

Communication

Time Management

Teamwork

Growth Mindset

Persistence

Personal Responsibility

Work History

AWS RESTART PROGRAMME STUDENT, GENERATION UK&I

June 2020 → September 2020

This 12 week fulltime programme covered classroom-based skills development and training on IT fundamentals. During the course I covered Linux, Python and Shell, in addition to AWS. This included learning about and becoming familiar with the monitoring and support of AWS and how to apply these services in the area of compute, storage and networking, including EC2, S3, IAM, VPC, Lamda,

Cloud Formation, RDS and Route 53. Finally, during this programme I also developed my professional skills, resulting in improvements to my verbal and written communication. I also gained experience of explaining technical information and terminology to non technical end users.

RETAIL STAFF, FAST CAR DIRECT

October 2017 → May 2018

Working with a team of 3 to 5 people each day, my duties involved attending to customers in person and over the telephone, packaging parcels to specification ready for dispatch, creating advertisement posters in Photoshop, testing technical products for defects and providing technical support to all departments when needed. Having such a variety of different responsibilities during my time here showed my versatility in work, as well as my time management skills to be able to prioritise and complete all tasks on schedule.

CUSTOMER SUPPORT ASSISTANT, MULTIMEDIA INTERNET CAFÉ

August 2009 → October 2017

My duties involved setting up the store before opening; this involved ensuring that shelves were stocked and computers were ready for use by the customers. Once the café had opened, it was my personal responsibility to assist customers and troubleshoot any issues they experienced. This included handling problems with printers and troubleshooting technical hardware-based faults with the computers themselves.

Education & Certifications

CERTIFICATIONS (YOUR ACCLAIM)

2020

AWS re/Start Graduate

Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

2018

CompTIA A+ ce Certification

HEATH PARK BUSINESS & ENTERPRISE COLLEGE

2007 - 2009

GCSE in Mathematics - Grade A

GCSE in English – Grade B

GCSE in Applied Science – Grade B

OCR Level 2 National Award in ICT - Pass

BTEC First Certificate in Business Studies - Merit

BTEC First Diploma in Art and Design – Merit

References available On Request